JAMES WOLFE

THE BEST CODER

✓ Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com

<a

SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in programming and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment such as the AWS Cloud, web development, Linux, and computer technology troubleshooting.

SKILLS

- o Hardware Troubleshooting o Joomla & WordPress o AWS Cloud o Java
- Server Troubleshooting
 HTML & CSS
 SSH
 RedHat

PROJECTS

Portfolios - Database Websites GitHub Repository

- Developed and maintained HTML and CSS websites using the services S3, Azure Container, Surge CLI, and GitHub Pages.
- Created custom domain name using Google domains and input the resource records and CNAME to the respective locations.
- Applied Agile best practices utilizing Trello's Kanban board tool.

Serverless Application GitHub Repository

- Launched a word processor application on AWS Amplify utilizing the CLI and configuring the REST framework backend files.
- Application files maintained and edited on GitHub repositories and Atom.

Headless Media Center

- Utilized Volumio after mounting the bootable program to a Raspberry Pi through the Linux based OS and entering Linux commands to connect the Volumio device to the phone application and account.
- Maintained and worked on the device using respective hardware and output the media player through Fender Squier 4 speakers
 connected using respective audio and power cables.

Computer Building and Troubleshooting

- Researched and budgeted computer hardware components and built the box while diagnosing issues with the booting, temperature, and cable management for peers and myself.
- Maintained the boxes by doing regular file cleaning, back-ups, hardware cleaning, and preventative measure programs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Woodworker Sue's Antiques

06/2021 — Present

• After purchasing and finding old and damaged antique furniture and items, I refurbish them utilizing sanding and stanning techniques, then resell the 18th and 19th century antiques in a variety of store locations, making the highest quality antique refurbished furniture.

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

 Solved server related issues such as unable to POST and after analyzing the issue I diagnose the software or hardware by reseating hardware components, CAT5/6 cables, or rebooting the servers which resolved tickets.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 — 01/2019

• While working in a fast-paced environment and multi-tasking, I managed my time effectively and made use of a step-by-step process taking orders, serving food and drinks, and welcoming new customers to provide the best quality customer service.

Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

- Faced with nutritional and health related issues for customers pets while working independently, I worked through problems by asking
 pet related questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve a customer concern and did it effectively by
 utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.
- Volunteered with Homeward Trails, German Shepherd Rescue, and PetValu by feeding, cleaning, and playing providing comfort and joy for the pets.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner

7BEZSG02PNEEQ83D

Agile Scrum Fundamentals

ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp

ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College Computer Science, Assembly Language, and Calculus II 2016-2020